Finding Aid for University of Michigan Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor, Alva Gordon Sink Group Records, 1959-2015
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
University of Michigan Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor, Alva Gordon Sink Group Records
1959-2015
University of Michigan. Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor. Alva Gordon Sink Group.
0563 Bimu H6 2
The Alva Gordon Sink Alumnae Chapter was established in 1959/60 as an offshoot of the University of Michigan Alumnae Association. The Sink Group provides financial support and mentorship to women attending the University of Michigan through scholarships, annual fundraising and social events. Materials include administration materials, officer records, newsletters, and membership directories.
1.5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by the organization (donor no. 9475 ) in May 2004.
The record group is open to research.
The Alva Gordon Sink Alumnae Chapter was founded during the school year 1959/60 by Alva Gordon Sink and a group of female students attending the University of Michigan. Sink was an alumnus of the University of Michigan and the wife of the University Musical Society Director Charles A. Sink. As well as being instrumental in the formation of the Sink Alumnae Chapter she was also a founding member of the first University of Michigan Alumnae Association in Ann Arbor and of the Sarah Browne Smith Alumnae Group.
The Alva Gordon Sink group was started with the goal to set up a scholarship fund for current female students at the university, therefore fundraising was an early aspect of the groups work. They used bake sales, garage sales, annual tasting parties, and the sale of cookbooks and hand-sewn university flags to raise money for their scholarships fund. The group also organized many social events for their members such as lecture series that took place at local museums or historical libraries and involved professors speaking on topics ranging from drugs and politics to horticulture and American history.
The Sink chapter continues to mentor female students and raise money for their scholarship fund through social events and fundraising activities. The chapter is one of four U-M alumnae chapters located in Ann Arbor, MI. It is directly affiliated with the Alumnae Council and the University of Michigan Alumni Association and participates in the events of the larger groups.
The records of the University of Michigan Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor, Alva Gordon Sink Group contain information about the founding of the group, its programs, activities, and membership. The records include correspondence, minutes, membership directories, and newsletters. The records are divided into five series, Administration, Officer Records, Newsletters and other mailings, Directories, and Yearly Files.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor. Alva Gordon Sink Group.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); Sink, Alva Joanna Gordon.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae--Michigan--Ann Arbor.Alumni and alumnaeMichiganAnn Arbor.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.
- Administration
  The Administration series consists of by-laws, fundraising materials, information on guest speakers that were invited to the university by the Sink Group, recruitment activities, officers list, the first president's manual from 1962, and information about their scholarship program.
  - By-Laws, 1959-1993 (Box 1)
  - Fundraising, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Guest Speakers, 1994-1999 (Box 1)
  - Membership Recruitment, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Officer List, 1959/60-1976/77 (Box 1)
  - President's Manual, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
  - Scholarship Information, 1989-1998 (Box 1)
  - Minutes, September 2012-May 2015 (Box 1)
- Officer Records
  The Officers Records form the majority of the collection. They consist of meeting minutes, annual reports, committee reports, event planning materials, and a small amount of documentation pertaining to the group's participation in the U-M Alumnae Council.
  - Pres. Elizabeth Gyorey, 1959/60 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Rae Weaver, 1960/61-1961/62 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Betsy Ince, 1962/63 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Jennie Lombard, 1963/64 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Mary Gelinas, 1964/65 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Mary Haddad, 1965/66 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Nan Bielby, 1966/67 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Carol Poltorak, 1967/68 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Carol Geyer, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Sue Cremin, 1968/69 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Carol McLean, 1969/70 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Connie Amick, 1970/71 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Mary Yeager, 1971/72 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Ann Maly, 1972/73 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Carole A. Katz, 1973/74 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Toni Reese, 1974/75 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Patricia More, 1975/76 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Karen O'Neal, 1976/77 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Sally Roach, 1977/78 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Louise Mattick, 1978/79 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Betsy Hubbard, 1979/80-1980/81 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Jennie Lombard, 1981/82 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Connie Amick, 1982/83 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Liz Elling, 1983/84 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Sandra B. Jameson, 1984/85 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Pat Dsida, 1985/86 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Fran Lyman, 1986/87 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Ann Maly, 1987/88-1988/89 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Peg Eibler, 1989/90-1990/91 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Jennie Lombard, 1991/92 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Sue Cremin, 1992/93 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Eleanor Shaw, 1993/94 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Elva Rosenzweig, 1994/95 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Liz Elling, 1996/97 (Box 1)
  - Pres. Peg Eibler, 1997/98 (Box 1)
- Newsletters and mailings to members
  The Newsletters and mailings to members series contains newsletters published roughly 2 to 3 times a year, in some years there were no newsletters published. These discuss chapter fundraising, social events, recruitment, and news about members.
  - 1967-1997 (Box 1)
  - Fall 2015 (Box 1)
- Directories
  The Directories span the years 1960/61 to 2009/10.
  - Member Directories, 1960/61-1984/85 (Box 1)
  - Member Directories, 1985/86-2014/15 (Box 1)
    (missing 2004/05)
- Yearly files
  The Yearly files contain a mixture of reports, correspondence, e-mail communications photographs, and membership miscellanea.
  - 1996/1997-2011/2012, 11 folders (Box 2)
    (include 50th anniversary brochure, 2010)
Related Material
Researchers interested in the Alva Gordon Sink Group records may also wish to consult these archival collections:
Charles Sink papers
Henderson House (University of Michigan) records
Alumni Association (University of Michigan) records
Center for the Education of Women (University of Michigan) records
University of Michigan Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor, Margaret L. Waterman Group records
University of Michigan Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor. Sara Browne Smith Group records
Alumnae Club of Ann Arbor. Lucille B. Conger Alumnae Group (University of Michigan) records
Martha Cook Alumnae Association records
.